Elijah Blaisdell

Seattle, WA | 206-225-1482 | elijahblaisdell@gmail.com

LinkedIn: /elijahblaisdell | GitHub: /elijah415hz | Portfolio: elijah415hz.herokuapp.com

SUMMARY

Full Stack Web Developer and international classical musician with a deep understanding of effective team collaboration. Skilled and persistent problem solver who writes clean, elegant code. A passionate craftsman and creative thinker who is proficient in solving large problems by iterating quickly. Very quick study, accustomed to performing under pressure, and experienced in adapting to client requests.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: Python, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, SQL, NoSQL

Applications: Github, MongoDB, MySQL

Tools: Node, Express, React, Handlebars, ¡Query, Bootstrap, Flask, Pandas, Matplotlib

PROJECTS

Flask of Finances | github.com/elijah415hz/finances-flask-public | flask-of-finances.herokuapp.com

- A progessive web app that gives highly granular insights into your finances.
- Fully customizable categories and offline functionality give you complete control.
- React, Typescript, Python, Flask, Pandas, Chart.js, MySQL, JSON web tokens.

Cozy Baby | github.com/elijah415hz/portfolio | cozy-baby.netlify.app/

- A custom-built temperature sensor to record indoor temperature fluctuations and compare them to outdoor temperatures.
- Data is gathered with a RaspberryPi equipped with a temperature sensor and is served to the frontend by an AWS Lambda function. See the README on Github for a full tutorial of the setup.
- React, Typescript, Python, Chart.js, Linux, AWS Lambda, MongoDB

Patched | github.com/elijah415hz/we-patch | we-patch.herokuapp.com

- A full-stack web application to connect people looking for gardening space to people who have space they'd like to share. Built using Leaflet.js, bcrypt, Nodemailer, and Cloudinary.
- HTML, CSS, JavaScript, ¡Query, Foundation, Sequelize, Handlebars, Express-Sessions.

EXPERIENCE

Web Developer Intern | Framewrk | 2021-present

- Building a React/Firebase production application with chat-bot functionality on a small, fast-moving team
- Shipping new features weekly to add value to this young startup

Freelance classical singer | New York City, 2014-2020 | www.elijahblaisdell.com

- 2018 Grammy-award winner with The Crossing
- Rapidly built a large client base of top organizations across the country, achieving 20% growth in gross revenue each year.
- Managed multiple, simultaneous collaborative projects in different genres and languages (German, Italian, French, Swedish)
- Coordinated and adapted efficiently (and often wordlessly) in new environments with unfamiliar colleagues Shift Manager | Starbucks | Boston, 2014-2015
 - Managed a team of 4-6 baristas to optimize efficiency and customer satisfaction by constantly improving our implementation of company methods
 - Oversaw inventory to ensure proper stock and trained new employees in coffee brewing and customer service

EDUCATION

Coding Bootcamp in Full Stack Web Development | University of Washington Master of Music in Vocal Performance | New England Conservatory Bachelor of Music in Vocal Performance | Central Washington University